荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
你有什么打算？
What's your resolution?
- 我打算减肥
- 可你是墨西哥人
- I'm going to cut carbs.
- Aren't you Mexican?
奶奶做的东西你都不能吃了
You can't eat nothin' Grandma makes.
养成一种习惯只要30天
It only takes 30 days to form a habit
之后就会变成第二天性
and then it becomes second nature.
根据真实事件改编
- 谁说的？
- 奥普拉
- Who says that?
- Oprah.
奥普拉？
（著名脱口秀主持人）
OK. Oprah cool now?
你有什么打算？
What's yours?
我不想再贩卖大麻
I want to quit selling trees.
弗鲁特韦尔地铁站
2009年新年
加州，奥克兰市
凌晨2:15
- 为什么不让我们走？
- 我不知道
- Why are we still here?
- I don't know. . .
看那个拍照的家伙
Look at that man taking pictures and shit.
坐下，闭嘴
Sit down! Shut the fuck up!
- 嘿
- 别动手
- Hey!
- Hey, come on, man!
别动手
Come on, now!
注意你的身份
Protect and serve!
- 别动手
- Come on, man.
- Come on now, y'all!
- 真的？
- 你这个黑鬼
- Really?
- Bitch-ass nigger, huh?
你这个黑鬼
Bitch-ass nigger, aren't ya?
这里有情况
Hey, that's hella fucked up!
有情况
That's fucked up!
放了他，搞什么
Let him go! What the fuck?
片名：《弗鲁特韦尔车站》
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：筱宸葭
校对：筱宸葭
等等，等等
Hold up, hold up.
加州，海沃德
2008年新年前夕
上午12:10
苏菲娅，我已经忍很久了
Fuck, Sophina.I've been holding, how long?
我不知道
I don't know.
每次你碰我
Every time you touch me,
我都会想到你和那个贱人亲热
all I can think about is
how you was touching that bitch.
你老是揪着这事不放
I'll never hear the end of that shit.
你知道吗？
You know what?
你说的对，去吧
You're right. Go.
我去干嘛？
What I gotta do? Hm?
我就和她搞过一次
Fucked with her that one time.
是你被抓到一次
Nah. You got caught. . . one time.
别跟我说
Are you gonna sit here and tell me
那是你第一次和那个贱人鬼混
that was the first time
you kicked it with that bitch?
你之前没见过她？
You ain't never seen her before that, huh?
都过去了
That shit's over with.
我要的是你和T
All I want is you. . . and T.
永远
Forever.
你说永远是什么意思？
What you mean, forever?
等下你就知道了
Let me show you.
爸爸？
Daddy?
- 快去
- 她叫的是你
- Go help.
- Mm-mm. She's asking for you.
- 怎么了？
- 我睡不着
- What's up?
- I can't sleep.
睡不着
You can't sleep.
你想和爸爸妈妈一起睡吗？
You want to sleep in here
with Mommy and Daddy?
- 嗯
- 好
- Mm-hm.
T，你怎么这么不懂事，几点了？
T, you know better than that.
What time is it?
下半夜了
It's after midnight.
（发送短信给妈妈：生日快乐！！！）
妈妈，今天我能带两份果干吗？
Mommy? Can I have
two fruit snacks today?
不行，你可以多带一个苹果
No, you can have
an extra apple if you want.
- 妈妈
- 别跟我争
- But, Mommy. . .
- Don't argue with me, T.
太早了
It's too early.
- 我们得给车加油
- 剩下的油够开到幼儿园
- Oh, come on, we have to go get gas.
- We got enough to get us there.
嘘
Shh!
- 早上好，塔蒂阿娜
- 早上好，史黛西太太
- Good morning, Tatiana.
- Good morning, Mrs. Stacy.
- 你好吗，奥斯卡？
- 很好，你好吗？
- How you doin' today, Oscar?
- I'm doing good, you?
看到没，我说了油够了
See? Told you we'd make it.
你回家睡觉吗？
You're gonna go home and sleep, right?
我还有事，为晚上准备东西
Nah, I'm gonna head up to the job.
Get some stuff for tonight.
我死也不愿休息日来这
I'd rather die than come here on my day off.
我们会去旧金山吧？
We're gonna go to 'Frisco, right?
看烟花？
See the fireworks?
当然会去
Yeah. We'll do that.
- 好
- Cool.
那我下车了
All right, let me get in here.
你的脖子好咸
Mm. . . The back
of your neck is all salty.
- 不说拜拜？
- 拜拜
- Are you gonna say bye?
- Bye.
我也爱你
Love you, too!
（呼叫妈妈）
喂？
Hello?
再问一次，你今天生日也要去上班吗？
Last shot,right here.You sure you want to work on your birthday?
我过来接你去庆祝吧
I'm gonna come get you.
Let's go celebrate.
听着很诱人
Well, as tempting as that sounds,
但这儿要是没我会大乱的
this place would be a mess without me today.
好吧，要我买一些螃蟹吗？
OK. You still want me to pick up
a couple crabs for later, right?
好啊，你能买些…
Yes, and could you pick up
a couple of. . .
你在开车？
Are you driving?
- 是的
- 戴耳机了没？
- Yeah.
- Are you wearing your earpiece?
- 戴了
- 别骗我
- Yeah.
- Don't lie to me.
等一下
All right, hold on.
- 喂？
- 现在戴上了？
- Hello?
- Is it on now?
戴上了
Yeah.
你帮我买一些虾米
OK. Yeah. Get me a couple of packets
of dried shrimp.
到时给你钱
Stop by on your way
and I'll give you the money.
钱的事你不用管
Don't worry about that.
我晚上会给你钱
All right, then,
I'll pay you back tonight.
不用了，妈妈
Come on, Ma. Don't trip.
今天是你生日
You ain't payin' for nothin'
on your birthday.
我要忙了
OK, I need to run on in here, baby.
- 晚上见
- 好
- I'll see you later tonight?
- Yeah.
- 我爱你
- 我也爱你
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 奥斯卡
- 你好吗？
- Osc, what's good boy?
- What's good with you, bruh?
- 老样子，你找埃米？
- 他在吗？
- Yeah, same shit. You looking for Emi?
- Yeah, he here?
今天早些时候见过他，不知道现在他在哪
I seen that nigger earlier today, bruh.
I don't know where he at now.
- 对了，给我来些螃蟹
- 我想起来了
- Oh bruh, came to get some crabs, too.
- Crab. . . Ah shit, that's right.
- 今天是妈妈生日
- 对啊
- It's Ma's birthday today?
- Yeah.
不好意思，我忘了，替我跟她说生日快乐
My bad, I forgot.
Tell her I said happy birthday.
- 你怎么不自己去跟她说？
- 我今晚走不开
- Why don't you come tell her yourself?
- I can't do it tonight, boy.
- 我另有安排
- 少来了
- I gotta bust some moves.
- You ain't bustin' shit.
新年跨年有什么安排？
What's good for the countdown though?
去旧金山看烟花
You know, 'Frisco,
fireworks, the whole shit.
- 明白吗？
- 明白
- Feelin' me?
- Yeah, yeah.
要帮忙吗？
Need help?
我要一磅…
Uh, yeah. Can I get a pound of your. . .
我能看看鳎目鱼长什么样吗？
Can you show me what your sole looks like?
可以
Yeah.
- 鳎目鱼
- 好
- Sole.
- Uh. . . OK.
我能看看鲶鱼吗？
What about your catfish? Can I see that?
- 这就是鲶鱼
- 我想做炸鱼
- Yeah, cat.
- OK, I want to do like, a fish fry.
这种鱼可以吗？
Are these ones good to fry?
开什么玩笑，是鱼都可以
What the fuck, man. It's fish.
You can fry all of it.
稍等一下
Right. . . Just give me a second.
你要给妈妈买什么？
Yeah. What do you need for Moms, bruh?
我要三个丹金尼斯大海蟹，去后面拿
Let me get three Dungeness Crab.
From the back, bruh.
要肥一点的，别耍我
Fat ones, too. Don't try and play me.
新年晚餐准备做炸鱼？
So, you're having a fish fry
for New Year's or something?
差不多吧
Uh, yeah. Something like that.
我在这上班，我可以帮你
Oh, I work here.
I can help you figure it out.
今天我休息
It's my day off.
我想在去旧金山前给一个朋友做顿饭
Um. . . Well, I'm cooking for a friend
tonight before we go to the city,
他喜欢吃南方风味的炸鱼
and he loves fried fish,
like Southern style. . .
- 南方风味，他是黑人？
- 不，他是白人
- Southern. Sounds like he's black.
- Oh, no, he's white.
他应该认识不少黑人
But he knows a lot of black people, I guess.
噢
Uh-huh.
我自己完全没头绪
I don't know what I got myself into.
（呼叫邦妮奶奶）
- 喂？
- 奶奶
- Hello?
- Grandma?
奥斯卡，你好吗？
Oscar, how you doin', baby?
- 我在上班
- 你在上班？
- I'm at work and I got this. . .
- You're at work?
- 是的，奶奶
- 拜拜
- Yeah, Grandma.
- Bye.
不不不，奶奶，今天我休息
No, no, no, Grandma.
It's my day off, all right?
- 我在为晚餐买东西
- 不好意思
- I'm shopping for the party tonight.
- Oh, l'm sorry, baby.
我以为你在玩手机
I thought you were playing on the phone.
没有，奶奶，我这有位顾客
Oh no, Grandma.
But I do have this customer here.
她想做炸鱼，但是不知道怎么做
She wants to have a fish fry,
but she don't know how.
你能告诉她怎么做吗？
You think you can tell her
everything she needs to know?
没问题，她想做什么炸鱼？
Oh, no problem, baby.
What kind of fish does she want to fry?
奶奶，她也不知道
Grandma, she don't know.
她不知道自己要做什么炸鱼？
She don't know what kind
of fish she wants to fry?
是的，奶奶
Nah, Grandma, nah.
让她接电话
Put her on the phone.
- 她怎么称呼？
- 邦妮奶奶
- What's her name?
- Grandma Bonnie.
你好，邦妮奶奶
Hi, Grandma Bonnie.
埃米来了
There's Emi's right there, bruh.
我叫凯蒂，你好
. . . Katie. It's nice to meet you.
- 早啊，埃米
- 奥斯卡，什么事？
- Hey, good morning, Emi.
- Oscar. What's going on?
给我妈妈的生日准备东西
Trying to pick up some stuff
for my Mom's birthday.
东西都买齐了吧
Hope you found everything you need.
我想跟你说几句
Yeah, I just want to talk to you
for a second.
现在不行，节假日忙死了
It's a little nuts right now,holiday and all.
我想谈谈我工作的事
Look, I want to talk about my job.
- 职位已经满了
- 埃米
- The position's been filled.
- Look, look, Emi
我真的很需要这份工作
Look, I really need this job, all right?
过去我的处境很糟，我现在想重新开始
I was going through some shit before
trying to get back on my feet,
你知道我需要这份工作
you feel me, but. . . I need this.
你可以让我每周一班，我没意见
You can start me off with one shift
a week or whatever, I'll be here.
付我一半工资就行
Work me 40 hours, only pay me for 20. . .
我已经雇了别人
Dude, I hired somebody else.
我如果让你回来，就得开除别的员工
For me to bring you back, that means
I have to let someone else go.
从没迟到过一次的员工
Someone who's never showed up late once.
不好意思，我喜欢你这人
I'm sorry, I like you, man. . .
我需要这份工作
I need this fuckin' job, bruh.
你想我贩毒吗？
You want me sellin' dope, bruh?
奥斯卡
Oscar. . .
要我在外面等你忙完再谈吗？
You need me outside waiting
for you to get done, bruh?
你自己保重
You take care of yourself.
嘿
Hey!
我现在成专家了
I'm an expert now.
看来怎么做你都清楚了
See you got everything you need.
都清楚了，谢谢你
I've got everything, thank you.
不用谢
No problem.
- 还给你
- 噢
- Here you go.
- Oh.
我叫凯蒂
I'm Katie, by the way.
- 奥斯卡
- 新年快乐
- Oscar.
- Happy New Year.
- 新年快乐
- 怎么样？
- Happy New Year.
- What's up, bruh?
- 埃米人很好
- 他让你回来工作？
- Emi was good.
- He put you back on?
- 下个星期开始
- 那就好
- Starting next week.
- That's what's up.
保重，我们今晚庆祝
Take it easy, man.
We celebrating tonight.
- 别迟到
- 不用担心
- Can you not be late?
- Don't even worry about that, man.
- 记得接电话，注意安全
- 好的
- Just answer your phone. Be safe, bruh.
- All right. Yep.
（香蒂来电）
- 喂？
- 笨蛋，你好吗？
- Hello?
- Hey chump, what's up?
- 你在干嘛？
- 刚下班回来
- What are you doin'?
- Just got back in from the job.
我以为今天你休息
l thought you was off today?
- 是的
- 你打给妈妈没？
- I am.
- You call Mom yet?
- 打了，你呢？
- 打了
- Yeah, did you?
- Yeah.
我有一些好消息和坏消息
But I got some good news
and some bad news.
先说坏消息
Gimme the bad news first.
我这个月的租金还没凑齐
I'm gonna need some help
with rent this month.
- 差多少？
- 300块
- How much?
- Like, 300.
我过几周就还你
But l can get you back
in a couple of weeks.
可以，好消息是什么？
OK, so what's the good news?
- 我今晚得加班
- 不是吧，香蒂
- I'm doing overtime tonight.
- Come on, Chantay.
我必须加班，再说妈妈会理解的
l gotta do it. Plus, Moms understands.
替我给妈妈买张卡片并写好祝福语
But I need you to get her a card
for me and sign it, all right?
没问题
All right.
别买有白人的那种，要黑人卡片
Osc, don't get me no fake-ass card with
no white people on it.I want a black card.
- 没问题
- 好的
- All right, I got you.
- All right.
- 我爱你
- 我也爱你，捣蛋鬼
- I love you, all right?
- Love you too, screw up.
拜拜
Whatever, bye.
（呼叫马库斯）
什么事，奥斯卡？
What's up with it, Osc?
你好吗，老兄，昨晚是我的错
What's good with it, bruh?
My bad about last night.
你还想要吗？
Still trying to get that?
不过我不会去那边，我一整天都在镇上
Hey, I'm not out that way though.
I'm gonna be in the town all day.
没事，我可以来找你
It's cool, I can come to you, bruh.
那好，我们在80号公路海边碰头
All right, meet me over here
by the water. Right off the 80.
大概一小时到
Gimme about an hour.
- 没问题
- 行
- All right, bet that.
- Bet.
就这个
Yeah.
嘿
Hey. . .
好狗狗
What's up, boy?
What's up, boy? What's up?
（发送短信给苏菲娅：要我中午过去吗）
（苏菲娅：已经取了）
嘿嘿嘿，停车
Hey! Hey! Hey, slow down!
停车，混蛋
Hey! Hey! Slow down!
You bitch motherfucker!
停车
Slow down!
怎么样？
Hi. What's up, bruh?
怎么样，没事的
What's up, bruh? It's all right, bruh.
没事的
It's all right.
It's all right, bruh.
没事的，还有我呢
It's all right, bruh. . .
You with me, bruh?
坚持住
Come on, bruh. . .
Come on.
谁来帮帮我
Somebody help!
格兰特
Grant, come on.
给我看看你的手、耳朵
All right, let me see
your hands. . . ears. . .
圣昆丁联邦监狱
加州，圣拉斐尔
2007年新年前夕
头发、嘴巴
. . .your hair. . . inside your mouth.
转身
All right, turn around.
弯腰，蹲下
Bend over, squat.
可以了
All right, you're good.
- 孩子
- 妈妈
- Hey baby.
- Hey Mama.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
你脸怎么了？
What happened to your face?
你今天气色不错
You look nice today.
塔蒂阿娜昨晚去看你了吗？
My girls came to see you last night?
- 我们一起玩了棋盘游戏
- 你一定会让她赢
- We played board games.
- I bet y'all let her win, too.
- 当然
- 太弱了
- Of course.
- Y'all hella weak for that.
她没这么容易赢我
She'll get no easy wins around me.
- 嗯
- 怎么了？
- Mm.
- What?
还记得前阵子你带回来的爆米花吗？
Remember that microwave popcorn
you bought a while back?
- 很好吃
- 是的
- Hella good.
- Yeah.
我把爆米花倒进碗里
While I was putting it in the bowl,
塔蒂阿娜站在那瞪着我
Tatiana just standing there,staring up at me,
好像她想要什么
looking like she wanted something.
后来呢，说啊
OK, then what? Come on, Ma.
她问我，外婆，有高脂奶油吗？
She says, "Grandma,
do we have any dark butter?"
高脂奶油？
Dark. . . What's dark butter?
我想她可能在美食频道看到过
I'm thinking maybe she watched
Food Network or something.
我说，孩子，什么是高脂奶油？
I said, "Sweetheart, what's dark butter?"
她说，爸爸带我去看《机器人瓦力》时
And she said, "Well, when my daddy took me to see Wall-E,
他点的低脂奶油
he asked for light butter.
所以这次我要尝尝高脂奶油
So now I want to try some dark butter this time."
- 她很聪明
- 这是你妈妈？
- She too smart. . .
- This Moms right here?
- 她也是小偷？
- 你说她什么？
- She a snitch, too?
- What the fuck you say about my moms?
- 去你妈的
- 要不是这有警卫
- Fuck you and this bitch.
- Talking tough with these guards.
如果在外面我揍扁你
I'm gonna see your bitch-ass on the outside.
- 帕尔马黑鬼
- 混蛋
- Bitch-ass Palma Ceia nigger.
- Bitch-ass motherfucker.
- 奥斯卡
- 关你屁事
- Oscar. . .
- Fuck DGF!
- 有事吗？
- 去你妈的
- Is there a problem in here?
- Oh, fuck you!
- 有事吗？
- 没事
- Is there a problem here?
- No, we good.
现在没事
Yeah, we good for now.
没事
Yeah.
你妈的
Yeah, fucked up. . .
冷静点
Calm down.
奥斯卡
Oscar.
你脸怎么了？
What happened to your face?
高脂奶油
Dark butter. . .
她很注意别人说什么
She always listenin'.
她太聪明了
Too damn smart for her own good.
幼儿园的人说，我们可以让她早点上学
Pre-school said, we should think about
starting her in school early. . .
苏菲娅跟你说了吗？
Phina tell you that?
我们会让她上私立学校
Yeah, we'll put her in private school.
统一的校服
Uniforms.
那天我看了圣B小学
I was looking at Saint B the other day,
他们那里实行西班牙语和英语双语教学
and they got this new thing where they start 'em off
speaking Spanish,then they put them back on English. . .
我不会再来这里
I'm not coming here anymore.
什么？
What?
我不会再来监狱看你
I'm not coming here
for these visits anymore.
- 这是最后一次
- 我知道
- This is my last time.
- I know, I know. . .
这也是我最后一次犯事
I know, this is
the last time for me, too.
我不会再犯事
I told you that.
I ain't going down no more.
你让苏菲娅承担这一切而你却撒手不管
You wanna keep putting Sophina through
this, then you go right ahead, OK?
塔蒂阿娜不该经历这些，奥斯卡
But Tatiana? That baby
doesn't deserve this, Oscar.
她还不懂这些
She's too young to know what's going on.
我想这就是为什么她问我
So I guess that's why
she asked me why you love
你宁愿度假也不愿陪她
taking your vacations more
than you like being with her.
- 她不会这么说
- 你是说我骗你咯
- She ain't say that.
- Oh, so I'm a liar now.
你跟她说我爱她
Ma, you got to tell her I love her.
- 跟她说…
- 你自己跟她说吧
- Tell her I . . .
- Tell her yourself.
下次你打电话回家自己跟她说
The next time you call home,
you tell her yourself.
或者让她来这里看你
Or better yet,
let her come visit you here.
我
Yeah, but I . . .
她不需要知道
She don't need to be exposed. . .
你已经让她知道了
You already exposed her. . .
- 你已经让她知道了
- 这么说你不管我了？
- You already exposed her to this.
- So what, you gonna leave me?
你打算又不管我，你是什么妈妈？
You gonna leave me again?
What kind of mom is you?
你打算把我扔在这里不管？
You gonna fuck around
and leave me in here?
你从没要我回去
You ain't never had my fuckin' back anyway.
我一个人在这
I'm in here by myself.
- 我爱你，奥斯卡
- 你什么也不爱
- I love you, Oscar.
- You don't love nothin'.
真的
I do.
我为你祷告
And I'm praying for you.
等你出来时再见
I'll see you when you get home.
等等，抱下我好吗？
Hey Ma, hold up. Let me get a hug, Ma?
格兰特，回到探访区
Grant,back to the visiting area.
妈妈，对不起，走开
Hey Ma, I'm sorry!
Get the fuck out of here!
妈妈，对不起，至少抱下我，至少抱下我
Ma, I'm sorry! At least get a hug!
Ma, let me just get a hug!
妈妈，对不起，放开我
Hey Ma, I'm sorry!
Get the fuck off me!
放开我，妈妈，对不起
Hey Ma, I'm sorry!
妈妈，对不起，放开我
Ma, I'm sorry!
Get the fuck off me!
放开我，妈妈
Get the fuck off me, bruh!
Hey, Ma. . . !
没想到我们还能再碰面
Shit, bruh. I didn't think
we was ever going to hook up.
- 怎么了？
- 我没事
- What's good?
- I'm smooth.
我有好消息和坏消息
I got good news
and bad news, though, my nig.
别跟我说你没拿货
Don't tell me you ain't got it.
- 卖给了一个白人
- 真的，多少钱？
- Sold it to a white boy.
- For real? For how much?
付了我一千块
Gave me a rack for it.
我不会出这么高价钱
I wasn't gonna pay that high.
尽管我需要，好消息是什么？
I still need it, though. What's good?
给你的
For the drive up?
好极了
Right on, Osc.
不用付钱
No, you're good, bruh.
- 真的？
- 收下吧
- You sure?
- Take it.
好
Right on.
你要来一根吗？
Burn one with your boy
right quick, though.
不用，你抽吧
Nah, it's all you, bruh.
好的，保重
Right on, Osc.
All right, bruh. Be smooth.
保重
Yeah.
能马上送我去奶奶家换衣服吗？
Can you take me to my grandma's house
real quick to get changed?
可以
Yeah.
你买的什么蛋糕？
What kind of cake you get?
胡萝卜蛋糕
Carrot cake.
为什么不选冰淇淋的？
Why you ain't get ice cream?
又不是你生日
'Cause it ain't your birthday.
如果把你的东西放在我那里就方便多了
You know, it'd be hella easier
if you had your stuff at my spot, right?
你为什么不搬过来？
Why don't you just move in?
等你接T前不再在车里抽大麻那天
Maybe when you stop blowing trees
in the car before we pick up T.
能把车窗摇下来吗？
Can you roll down the window, please?
T，过来
Hey T! T! Come here.
- 爸爸
- 小家伙
- Daddy!
- Hey, what's up, nugget?
孩子
Hey, what's up, girl?
玩得开心吗？
How you doin'?
- 开心
- 开心？
- Good.
- Good?
今天我们玩了抓人游戏
We played freeze tag today.
是吗，你赢了没？
Really? Did you win?
- 他们抓不到我
- 你一定跑的很快
- They couldn't catch me.
- Think you fast, huh?
比爸爸还快？
Think you're faster than Daddy?
真的？
Mm. Really?
那是什么？
What's that?
嘿
Hey!
我打不败的，我打不败的
Undefeated! Undefeated!
你还没打败我，知道吗？
You still haven't beaten me yet.
You know that, right?
- 你干什么？
- 什么意思？
- What are you doing?
- What do you mean?
- 你把车弄坏了
- 没事的
- You're going to break this car!
- It'll be all right.
- 车都快散架了
- 我不能输，打不败的
- It's already falling apart.
- I can't lose. Undefeated.
爸爸无敌
Daddy's 100 and 0.
大骗子，你这个大骗子
Big, big, big cheater.
You're a cheater.
我没作弊
I didn't cheat.
你怎么知道我作弊？
How do you know if I cheated or not?
你刚才在车里，T，你妈妈怀恨在心
You were sitting in the car.
T, Mommy's a hater.
- 奶奶？
- 什么事？
- Grandma?
- Yes?
今晚你能照看下T吗，我们要去旧金山
Can you watch T tonight?
We want to go to 'Frisco.
问你姐姐
Ask your sister.
但是罗斯要照看好几个孩子
But Rose got hella kids to watch.
照看六个或七个孩子有区别吗？
But what's the difference
between watching six kids or watching seven kids?
（西班牙语）
爸爸，你衣服上是什么？
Daddy, what's that on your shirt?
爸爸工作时出了点意外
Daddy had an accident at work.
工作的事怎么样？
How is work, by the way?
工作就是工作
Work is. . . work.
我等下回来
I'll be back.
这件怎么样？
What you think?
挺好看
It's cool.
床上那件衣服是给你的
Put a shirt on the bed
for you, if you want.
我换上
Right on.
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
奥斯卡，怎么了？
Osc. . . What's up?
嗯？
Hm?
我工作丢了
Fuck it. I lost my job.
为什么？
For what?
上班迟到
Being late.
前阵子想挣点钱
Last couple of days,
trying to get some money.
他们今天告诉你的？
And they told you today? On your day off?
两个星期前的事了
Can I keep it real?
They told me two weeks ago.
我的错，苏菲娅
My bad, Phina.
我以为可以要回工作
I thought I was gonna get my job back. . .
你以为生活闹着玩的吗？
You think life's a fucking joke?
你以为被开除了
You think you're gonna get fired
有人会给你工作吗？
and somebody's gonna
give you your job back?
你现在打算怎么办？
What? What game you running now, Osc?
你什么都不是
You ain't shit, you know that?
你对我撒谎，对你自己的女儿撒谎
You lie to me, you lie
to your fucking daughter. . .
我不该跟你说的，这样一切都会照旧
I ain't had to tell your ass nothing.
Food on the table, the lights still on.
我应该瞒着你的，你不用知道这些
I could've kept getting it,
you wouldn't have known shit.
你打算就这么瞒下去？
Oh, so you would've just kept faking?
然后整天在外面混
And been out there bustin' knocks,
and doing whatever else,or whoever else. . .
你说你想听真话
You say you want the truth, right?
你根本不听我说什么
You ain't even tryin' to hear me.
You ain't even trying to hear it.
你根本不听我说什么
You ain't even listening to me.
因为你瞒了两个星期，现在被逼入绝境，没得选择
Not after you lie for two weeks,
get cornered, and don't have a choice.
这不是男子汉的行为
That's some pussy-ass shit.
你今天干什么了？
What'd you do today? Huh?
你肯定去卖大麻了
I bet you sold that fucking zip.
我已经不做了
I dumped that shit, Phina.
我正想告诉你
That's what I'm trying to tell you.
我好累
I'm tired.
以为我可以重新来过
Thought I could start over fresh, but. . .
但事情没这么顺利
. . .shit ain't workin' out.
你没卖大麻又没找到工作？
You threw a whole zip of weed out
and you don't got a job?
我真想扇你
I could slap you right now.
你怎么办？
What are you gonna do?
做些合法的事
Something legal.
也许我可以好好的过30天
Maybe if I could just
not fuck up for 30 days.
奥普拉不是说养成一种习惯需要30天吗？
That's how long Oprah said
it takes to form a habit, right?
看着我
Look at me.
别再让我一人承担这些
Don't make me have to go
through this shit alone, again.
脱掉，脱掉
Get this off. Take it off.
“呐”和“哈”的发音明显不同
A distinct difference
between "Nah" and "Haa."
对
Yeah.
你们来的刚好
Hey, you guys are just in time!
生日快乐
Happy birthday!
你们给我买了生日蛋糕？
Oh, you guys got me a cake, too?
- 生日快乐
- 谢谢你，孩子
- Yup. Happy birthday.
- Thank you, baby.
好香啊
Smells good in here.
下来
Here you go.
看看你
Look at you. . .
奶奶
Hey Grandma.
什么这么香？
What's smelling so good?
奥斯卡
Oh, Osc. . .
你知道我只要两个，你不用花这么多钱
Baby, you know I only needed two.
You didn't have to spend so much money.
妈妈，这个你不用担心
Mama, you don't gotta worry about that.
- 噢
- 好吧
- Oh. . .
- OK.
- 干嘛呢？
- 在做坏事
- What's up?
- We're up to no good. . .
- 你们好吗？
- 你好吗，奥斯卡？
- How you guys doing?
- How you doin', Oscar?
一切都好吗，奥斯卡？
What's going on, Oscar?
- 都挺好的
- 真的？
- Nothin', hangin' out.
- Yeah?
弄点吃的，我饿了
Get some food. I'm hungry.
你拿的什么？
Uh-oh, what you got?
给妈妈的卡片
Mom's card.
香蒂让我替她买张卡片
Tay wanted me to go pick her up one.
- 给你
- 谢谢
- There you go.
- Appreciate that.
她看到这个一定会疯掉
She's gonna flip out over this one.
- 不是吧
- 那是香蒂
- Oh, come on, now.
- That's Chantay there.
拿东西进来了，把它放在…
We got stuff comin' in.
You want to put it in. . .
不能扔掉
You can't dump it!
我这么小的时候她就这样对我说的
No, that's what she told me when I was this size.
“不能扔掉”
"You can't dump it!"
T，你爸爸像你这么小的时候
You know, T,when your daddy was your size,
他经常跟我和奶奶做这些
just your age, he used to do this
with me and grandma.
是的，不过他没你做的好
Yes, he did, but he didn't do
it nearly as well as you're doing it.
没错，他洗过的我都得重新洗
No, he did not. I had to re-crack
everything he cracked.
苏菲娅，你们很相爱
Sophina, you are in love, honey.
- 是的
- 因为他不是大考验
- I am.
- 'Cause he was not a great try.
你觉得这届超级碗哪个队会赢？
Who you think gonna win the Super Bowl?
- 钢人队
- 钢人队？
- The Steelers.
- Steelers?
- 是的，钢人队
- 什么？
- Yeah, the Steelers. Yeah.
- What?
突击者的球迷支持钢人队
A Raiders fan cheerin' for the Steelers.
Yes, a Raiders fan cheerin' for the Steelers.
黑色队服、黑人球员、黑人教练
Black uniforms,
black players, black coach.
教练的老婆也是黑人，我支持钢人队
Coach even has a black wife.
I'm going for the Steelers.
你疯了
You insane!
我知道自己疯了
I know I'm insane.
You know I'm insane?
- 开饭啦
- 马上来
- It's ready.
- All good!
你不伺候我们？
You ain't goin' to serve us?
我从没伺候过你，塞费斯
I didn't serve you your whole life, Cephus.
开饭啦
OK, get us somethin' to eat!
来段美食舞蹈
Doin' my food dance.
我的盘子呢，旺达？
Where my table tray, Wanda?
你的盘子在你房间，达里尔
I got your table tray
at your house, Daryl.
塞费斯，刚才是你？
Oh, Cephus, that was you?
那是塞费斯，你知道不是我
That was Cephus,you know that wasn't me. . .
不好意思，达里尔，不好意思
I'm sorry, Daryl. I'm sorry.
给你的，孩子，还要加点蟹肉吗？
Here you are, sweetheart. There you go.
You want a little more crab?
够了
I'm good.
谢谢，谢谢
Oh, thanks. Thanks.
- 不要这样
- 你们够了
- None of that.
- All right, you all.
大家一起来
All right, everybody.
万能的主啊
Oh, Heavenly Father,
谢谢你让我们全家相聚
we thank you for having
our family together tonight.
我们很幸运能享受奶奶做的她拿手的汤
We are blessed that Grandma Bonnie made her famous gumbo.
谢谢你赐给我们丰盛的晚餐，阿门
In your name, let's feast. Amen.
阿门
Amen.
- 生日快乐，妈妈
- 最好的生日礼物
- Happy birthday, Mama.
- Best birthday present.
谢谢你今晚帮忙
Thanks for your help tonight.
妈妈，你不用谢我
Come on, Mama.
You ain't got to thank me.
我本来就不该让你做这些
I shouldn't even be letting you do this.
没事，很轻松
Oh, please. It's relaxing.
你爱说什么就说什么
Yeah, if you say so.
我说的
I say so.
你们今晚有什么安排？
You guys got plans for the night?
没什么重要的事
Yeah, nothing major though.
和伙伴们一起进城
Meet up with the fellas,
head out to the city.
你们出去玩还是？
You guys going out, out? Or. . .
我们会很低调的
I think we're just gonna be low-key.
看完烟花后也许会去逛逛
Catch the fireworks, probably
roll around a little bit after that.
逛逛？
Roll around?
放心
It's gonna be cool, though.
再说，苏菲娅明早还得上班
Chill. Plus, Phina's gotta get up
and go to work in the morning anyway.
你们会喝酒吗？
You guys gonna be drinking?
妈妈，他们会喝酒
Mama, they gonna be drinking.
我上次喝酒是什么时候都记不起来了
I haven't had a drink since. . .
I can't even remember.
要不你们坐地铁去吧
Why don't you take the train out there.
这样你们就可以喝酒，出去玩也没什么好担心的
That way you guys can drink and hang out
and not have to worry about anything.
我们去去就回
Nah, I feel like getting
over there and getting back.
- 不用做地铁
- 坐地铁还不堵车
- Not waiting on no train.
- No traffic, either.
去和回来的路上一定很堵
You know? You know it's gonna be crazy,
going and coming back.
我们也许会坐地铁
Yeah, we might take it.
别让我老盯着你们
Don't make me follow you guys to make sure.
记得毕业舞会的事吗？
Remember prom?
正想忘记
Trying to forget.
（发短信给克里斯：我们坐地铁去吧）
走了，我们得走了
We gotta go. We're gonna go, OK?
亲爱的，谢谢你
Honey, thank you.
没事吧？
You good?
- 我去拿东西
- 说再见了吗？
- Let me get my stuff.
- Did you say goodbye?
过来
Come here.
- 我们要走了
- 我爱你们
- We're outta here.
- I love you.
- 好的
- 不用起来，不用起来
- All right, now.
- Don't get up, don't get up.
你们去吧，玩得开心点
All right, so you going out.
All right, have fun.
新年快乐
Happy New Year.
好了
All right, all right.
- 我爱你
- 我也爱你
- Love you.
- Love you, too.
- 生日快乐
- 谢谢你，孩子
- Happy birthday.
- Thank you, baby.
- 过来
- 新年快乐
- Come here.
- Happy New Year.
新年快乐
Happy New Year.
我们今晚别去了吧
Let's just call it a night.
我要去
I'm going out.
我不管你干嘛，反正我要去旧金山
I don't know what you're doing,
but I want to go into 'Frisco.
我们可以在家观看新年倒计时活动
We can just watch
the countdown from the house.
不行
Mm-mm.
去吧，我想玩玩
Let's go out. I wanna have fun.
喝醉
Get drunk.
好吧
All right.
- 我们进城
- 真的？
- We'll go to the city.
- Yeah?
真的
Yeah.
- 新年快乐
- Happy New Year!
你们好壮
Oh no! You guys are so strong!
新年快乐
Hi, happy New Year.
别闹了，奥斯卡，我刚准备让他们睡觉
Come on, Osc.
I just got them ready for bed.
好痒啊，好吧，你赢了
That tickles! All right, you win!
孩子们，让叔叔起来，快点
Guys, let your uncle up. Come on.
- 让叔叔起来
- 你赢了，你赢了
- Let your uncle up.
- You win, you win!
快去睡觉
Go to bed. Come on.
去刷牙好吗？
Ready to go brush those teeth?
- 不好
- 不好？
- No.
- No?
如果不刷牙，你的牙齿会烂掉
'Cause if you don't,
your teeth is going to rot
你的口气就会像汤饭一样
and your breath's going
to start smelling like gumbo.
- 你喜欢这样吗？
- 喜欢
- You want that?
- Yes.
- 你不会喜欢的
- 喜欢
- No, you don't.
- Yes.
因为汤饭怪物会来抓你
'Cause then the Gumbo Monster
will get you!
爸爸
Daddy!
继续
Go on.
你也吃了汤饭
You had gumbo, too.
里面的牙齿也要刷
Get those chompers in the back.
下面
Down low.
差点就赢了我
You almost got me.
- 哎哟
- 怎么了
- Ouchie!
- Come on.
我的脚好痛
My feet hurt.
我们要走了
We're getting ready to take off, OK?
你们不在这里过夜吗？
You guys aren't going to sleep over, too?
我们已经答应朋友
We already promised our friends
今晚和他们出去
we was going to kick it with them tonight.
我们会在你起床前回来
But we'll be back before
you wake up though, OK?
不要走
No! Don't go.
我害怕
I'm scared.
怕什么？
Scared of what?
我听到外面有枪声
I hear guns outside.
那些是烟花的声音
You know what, baby?
Those is firecrackers.
你和表兄表姐们在屋里很安全
You're safe inside with your cousins.
那你呢，爸爸？
What about you, Daddy?
我？
Me?
我没事
Baby, I'm gonna be fine.
我告诉你
I'll tell you what, though.
你明天起床后，我们玩糖果乐园
When you wake up in the morning,
we're gonna play Candy Land.
你猜之后我们会做什么
And then guess what
we're gonna do after that.
- 去公园？
- 更好
- Go to the park?
- Better.
玩具反斗城？
Toys"R"Us?
比那更好玩
Way better than that.
为什么？
Why?
查克奶酪游戏屋怎么样？
I don't know, maybe. . . Chuck E. Cheese?
- 真的？
- 我保证
- Really?
- I promise.
爸爸会陪你玩遍所有游戏好吗？
Daddy's gonna give you hecka tokens
and we gonna play all the games, OK?
然后去吃你最爱的披萨
And then we're gonna get your favorite pizza,
我们把它全吃光
and we'll eat it all up.
包括妈妈的，因为她要减肥
Even Mommy's ,'cause she can't have carbs.
减肥？
What's a carb?
你现在不用担心这个
You ain't got to worry
about that right now.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你，爸爸
I love you, too, Daddy.
- 索尼娅…
- 两个
- Sonja. . . Nigga, I passed. . .
- Mm-hm. That's two.
我把她摊派给你了
I passed her on to you.
I be putting you on her.
我交过的两只手就数的过来
I can count all of mine on two hands.
奥斯卡人呢？
Where the fuck is nigga Oscar at, bruh?
他今天早些时候来找过工作
He came by the job earlier today.
- 他总是迟到
- 靠
- He's always late, bruh.
- Ah, damn, damn. . .
老是围着苏菲娅转
Fuckin' around with Sophina,always, bruh.
这就是男人的堕落
Damn, nigga.That's the downfall of man. . .
女人拖累男人
Bitch slowing a nigga down and shit.
说什么呢，准备走了吗？
Fuck all that shit,
y'all niggas ready to go?
嘿
Hey!
我们都在等你
We waitin' on you, nigga!
当然了，她得去梳妆打扮
Of course, it was, man. She had to get
her hair and shit and all that.
- 你好吗？
- 迟到鬼
- You, what up, bruh?
- Late-ass, nigga. . .
不能怪我
Hey man, it ain't me!
奥斯卡，为新年来一口
Osc, take a shot
for the New Year, nigga!
新年快乐，兄弟们
Happy New Year's, motherfuckers.
新年快乐
Happy New Year to you, too.
我没买票
I ain't got my ticket.
- 嘿
- 走吧
- Hey!
- Let's go, boys!
快点
Come on, man. . .
赶紧的
Hurry up, bruh.
车门关闭
Doors close.
- 新年快乐
- Hi, happy New Year.
- Happy New Year.
请不要毛手毛脚
Make sure you keep your hands to yourself.
在地铁吸烟可是违法的
Did you know it's illegal
to smoke blacks on the BART.
是吗，警官？
Is that right, Officer?
今天是节日，放你们一马
We're gonna let y'all slide
'cause it's a holiday and all.
口渴吗，你们要吗？
You thirsty? You guys good?
好极了
Right on, bruh. For sure.
我喜欢你的发型
I like your dreads.
我喜欢你的一切，我们应该在一起
Shit, I like your everything.
We need to put it together.
- 我们是同性恋
- 开什么玩笑
- Oh, we gay.
- No shit?
- 同性恋？
- 这么巧
- Gay, huh?
- Sounds like a coincidence.
我们也是同性恋
We gay, too.
你们才不是同性恋
You're not gay.
奥斯卡，我们是同性恋吗？
Hey Osc, bruh. Ain't we gay?
彻头彻尾的同性恋
Yeah, they gay as fuck.
到达西奥克兰站
Approaching West Oakland Station.
抱歉，各位乘客，列车稍微晚点
Sorry folks,there's gonna be a slight delay.
- 我们一定能赶到
- 我们赶不到了
- We gonna make it.
- No, we're not.
- 我们能赶到
- 现在几点？
- Yeah, we are.
- What time is it?
- 别这么消极
- 我不是消极
- Stop being so negative.
- I'm not being negative.
我们一定能赶到
You know we'll make it.
你好
What's up, bruh?
害我们要错过倒计时了
They're gonna fuck around
and miss the countdown.
我们不会错过
We ain't gonna miss shit.
我们可以在这里庆祝
We fixin' to get cracked right here.
抱歉，各位乘客，列车继续前行
Sorry folks.We're back on our way. . .
下一站，蒙哥马利站
Next stop, Montgomery Station.
有表吗？
Hey gotta watch?
把音乐关掉
Turn the music down, bruh.
10、9、8
Ten, nine, eight,
7、6、5
seven, six, five,
4、3、2、1
four, three, two, one!
新年快乐
Happy New Year!
你要买个新的
You gonna get a fresh one!
天啊
Oh, my God!
有人想方便吗，我得找个地儿方便下
Hey, do you gotta pee?
I gotta find somewhere to pee.
你不是刚从洗手间出来
You just left the bathroom.
那里太脏了，我不想在那方便
It's hella dirty in there,
I'm not gonna pee in there.
- 你一定很冷吧
- 我冷死了
- Now you have to be hella cold. . .
- I am hella cold.
你知道怎么做
And you know what's gonna happen.
- 我是年轻小伙
- 你是个绅士
- A young man right here.
- See? You are a gentleman.
他是绅士，这个手提包和你真配
He's a gentleman.
That purse looks real good on you, too.
你拿着这个手提包真配
You look real good in that purse.
说什么呢，作为男友，这是我应该做的
What? Look, as a boyfriend,
it's what I gotta do.
- 我憋不住了
- 我知道
- I gotta pee so bad.
- I know, I know.
问问这家店
Ask the store right here.
你好，能让我们用下洗手间吗？
What's up, bruh?
You got a bathroom that we could use?
我已经关门了
I'm all closed up, man.
我也没有供顾客使用的洗手间
And I don't even have
a bathroom for my customers.
你一定有供店员使用的洗手间吧？
But I'm sure you got a bathroom
for your employees, right?
我也没多少钱，明白我意思吗？
Say, bruh, I ain't rich at all,
you feelin' me?
这是我最后十块钱
Here's my last ten dollars.
要么你收下这十块，让他们用下洗手间
Now, you can take this ten,
let them use the bathroom,
要么你回家
or you can go home.
等你明天来时，这儿一定到处是小便
When you come back tomorrow,
there's gonna be hella piss here
她们总不能尿裤子里吧？
'cause they ain't gonna pee
on themselves, you feelin' me?
真的？
For real?
看看她
Look at her.
- 就这两位女士？
- 就这两位女士
- Just these two girls?
- Just these two girls.
去吧，小心脚下
OK, come on in. Just watch your step.
谢谢
Thank you.
不用了，新年快乐
Don't worry about it, man.
Happy New Year.
新年快乐
这儿一定有洗手间吧
Please tell me this place has a bathroom.
怎么了？
What?
她怀孕了
She's pregnant.
- 进来吧
- 谢谢
- OK, come on.
- Thank you.
- 谢谢你
- 不用谢
- Thank you.
- No problem.
- 不能再来人了
- 没问题
- No more.
- That's it.
保证是最后一个
Promise, last one.
- 多谢
- 不用谢
- Thanks a lot, man.
- No problem.
- 非常感激
- 没事
- Appreciate that.
- Yep.
还以为她只能在大街上解决
Thought she was gonna
have to go in the street.
我们也差不多
We almost had the same problem.
你们结婚多久了？
How long you guys been married?
八年
Eight years.
你打算结婚？
You thinkin' about it?
是什么在阻挠你？
What's stopping you?
- 没钱
- 很烂的理由
- No money.
- Ah, shitty reason.
- 我们结婚时一无所有
- 开什么玩笑？
- We had nothing when we got married.
- No shit?
我当时没工作，她是个老师
I wasn't working at all,and she's a teacher,
不过她挣的钱也不多
it's practically the same thing,
as far as money goes.
婚戒哪来的？
How'd you get a ring?
我偷的
I stole it.
说了我没钱，过去靠信用卡过活
Told you, I didn't have any money.
Used to be good with credit cards.
- 我不想再这样下去
- 我理解
- I would not go down that road.
- No, bruh. I'm cool on that.
之后我的生意开始有点起色
Seriously, but then
I got my business started,
送了她现在戴着那只戒指
got her the ring she wears now.
- 你做哪一行？
- 网页设计公司
- What do you do?
- Got a Web design company.
如果你有需要就打电话给我
Hit me up if you ever need anything.
- 皮特？
- 没错
- Peter?
- Yeah.
- 奥斯卡
- 幸会
- Oscar.
- Hi, nice to meet you.
幸会
Nice to meet you too, bruh.
她们出来了
Here they come.
- 好了吧？
- 好了
- You good?
- Yeah.
- 嗨
- 嗨，宝贝儿
- Hi.
- Hi, baby.
真高兴遇到你们
It was nice meeting you guys.
- 恭喜你们
- 谢谢
- Congratulations.
- Thanks again, man.
- 不用谢
- 保重
- No problem.
- You take care.
新年快乐
Happy New Year, bruh.
- 怎么了？
- 没事吧？
- What up?
- We good?
我们走吧
Yeah, man, we gotta get out!
- 别废话了
- 走吧
- Now you're talkin' about shit, man.
- Let's go.
快点
Come on.
下一站，弗鲁特韦尔站
Next stop,Fruitvale Station.
坐下
Sit down.
我没事，你去找个座位
I'm good, fool. Get a seat.
- 确定？
- 我没事
- You sure?
- I'm good.
我去找个座位
I'm gonna go find a seat.
好的
Sure, bruh.
借过
Excuse me.
嘿，嘿，奥斯卡
Hey! Hey! Oscar!
我是凯蒂
Hey! Katie, from the store.
- 嘿
- 你好吗？
- Hey, hey!
- How are you?
- 很好，很好，新年快乐
- 新年快乐
- I'm good, I'm good. Happy New Year.
- Happy New Year.
奥斯卡，帕尔马那鬼地方来的？
Oscar? Oscar from fuckin' Palma Ceia?
记得你冲我吼的事吗？
What's up with all that shit
you were hollerin'?
你妈的，今天别惹我
Look, fuck all that shit, all right?
This ain't the time, bruh.
你这个混蛋
Fuck that shit, bitch.
This is DGF, motherfucker.
- 奥斯卡，什么事？
- 叫克里斯过来
- Oscar, what's up?
- Get Chris for me!
- 这里是南海沃市，臭小子
- 他们在打奥斯卡
- It's South Hayward, bitch!
- They're jumping Oscar!
- 弗鲁特韦尔站
- 南方来的孬种
- Fruitvale Station.
- Punk-ass Southside niggas. . .
去他妈的
Fuck them niggas.
列车上有人打架
There's been an incident on the train.
大家冷静，警察马上就来
Stay calm , the police are on their way.
请大家保持冷静，警察马上就来
Please remain calm ,the police are on their way.
我们赶紧下车吧
Better get the fuck off this train, bruh.
警察来了，快回到车上去
The police, baby.Get back on the train now.
海沃德见，兄弟们，大家分开走
Meet me in Hayward.
Hey boys, div up. Split up, bruh.
明白吗？
You feel me?
你们三个到墙边去
You three, to the wall.
- 把手拿出来
- 你们两个，快点
- Get your hands out of your pockets.
- You two, let's go.
把手拿出来，面对着墙
Get your hands out of your pockets.
Against the wall.
- 快过去
- 你说什么？
- Get over there!
- Man, what you talkin' about?
美女，让这位警官冷静点
Hey sexy, tell this brute
to calm the fuck down.
- 好像不是真的警察
- 蹲下
- Wow. Like that ain't real police.
- Get down.
要不是你戴着徽章，我绝不客气
If you ain't had that motherfuckin'
badge, bruh, it'd be on, straight up.
参与打架的人马上下车
If you were involved in the
fight, get off the fuckin' train now!
别逼我进去揪你出来
Don't make me come in there and pull you off!
- 你，下车
- 去你的，我什么也没干
- You, off the train.
- Fuck you. I ain't doing shit.
- 过来
- 干什么？
- Get over here.
- What the fuck?
- 干什么
- 全部蹲下
- All right, bruh.
- Sit down with your girlfriends.
- 我听到了，我什么也没干
- 冷静点
- I hear you. I didn't do it, bruh.
- Damn, be cool, man.
你要逮捕我们吗，我们什么也没干
You arrestin' us?
'Cause we ain't do shit.
凭什么扣留我们？
What the fuck, you just gonna hold us?
我一直这么解释
That's what I've been
sayin' this whole time,
但这个美臀警察就是不听
but she don't want to listen with her cute ass.
- 闭嘴
- 你打黑人
- Shut up!
- Damn, kick a nigga. . .
你的同党呢？
Where are your friends at, huh?
- 我们没同党
- 没同党
- We ain't got no friends.
- Got no friends. . .
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what friends
you talkin' about.
我看到了一个庞克族
I see one of those punks right now.
站台需要支援
On the platform in need of backup.
没事的，兄弟，没事的
Whoa, it's cool, bruh.
It's cool, it's cool.
冷静，大家冷静
Chill out, just chill, chill. . .
蹲下，蹲回去
Stay down! Back up!
Sit the fuck down!
冷静点，冷静点
Be cool, man! Be cool!
别打他
Hey, don't be slammin' my man!
- 坐下，坐下
- 好的，冷静点
- Sit down! Sit down!
- All right, be cool!
你没事吧，你没事吧？
You good? You good?
你们不能这样
You all can't do no shit like that!
- 蹲下
- 冷静，冷静
- Back down!
- Be cool, be cool!
别碰他
Hey, don't fuckin' touch him!
- 你干什么？
- 趴下
- What the fuck is that about, man?
- Get yourself on the ground.
- 趴下
- 你想打我？
- Get on the ground!
- You want to sucker punch me like that?
- 去你的
- 庞克猪
- Fuck that, bruh!
- Punk-ass pig!
- 你没事吧？
- 没事
- You all right?
- Yeah, I'm good.
- 你要干嘛？
- 看你们要干什么
- What is wrong with you?
- All right, OK. S'up.
退回去，退回去，退回去
Back up! Back up! Get back!
我拿着手机就要电击我吗？
You gonna tase me if I have my phone?
我已经拍下了你的工号
Yeah, I got your badge number, bruh.
闭嘴，手机收起来
Shut the fuck up
and put that phone away!
没问题，你怕什么？
Yeah, all right. But why?
What you trying to hide, bruh?
看好这些混蛋，我去车上找目击者
You keep these assholes secured,
I'm gonna check the train for witnesses.
- 混蛋警察
- 我拍到你了
- Punk motherfuckers. Badge. . .
- I got you.
- 手机收起来
- 我们走吧
- Put the fuckin' phone away.
- Get the fuck out of here, bruh.
妈的，简直乱来
Fuck these, niggas. This is bullshit.
- 没事吧？
- 我没事，我没事
- Cool, bruh?
- I'm good, I'm good.
我们没事的，我没事
We're gonna be good. I'm good.
- 闭嘴
- 苏菲娅，怎么了？
- Shut up.
- Phina, what's up?
- 你还在车上吗？
- 没有，我们还在弗鲁特韦尔站
- Where you at? You still on the train?
- Hell no, we still at Fruitvale.
他们扣留了我们并且打我们
They holding us and beating on us and shit.
- 谁打你？
- 警察
- Who the fuck is beating on you?
- The fuckin' police.
- 别打电话
- 我等下就过来
- Get off your phone!
- I'm gonna get us out of here.
- 待会儿见
- 奥斯卡
- I'll meet you back, OK?
- Osc!
- 我爱你
- 这些混蛋警察
- I love you.
- These bitch-ass police.
没事，我们没事的
It's cool, bruh.
I'm gonna get us up outta here.
- 坐下，坐下
- 听我说
- Sit down, sit down!
- Let me talk with you. . .
给我坐下
Sit the fuck down.
- 天啊
- 别这样
- Jesus. . .
- Hey, come on, man.
- 干什么
- 坐下
- Fuck this bullshit!
- Sit!
没事，别怕，我们没事，我们没事
It's cool. You know what, man?
We good, bruh. We good, bruh.
随便他们扣留多久
They can hold us as long as they want,
他们不能无缘无故逮捕我们
but they can't arrest us
'cause we ain't do shit.
- 你说什么？
- 我说我们什么也没干
- What's that?
- I say we ain't do shit!
- 你们不能逮捕我们
- 是吗？
- Y'all can't fuckin' arrest us.
- Oh yeah?
把这两个铐起来，等着坐牢吧
Cuff these two assholes,
they're going to jail.
- 干嘛，你不能逮捕我们
- 这下满意了？
- Fuckin' what! You can't arrest us!
- How about that?
- 跪下
- 你不能逮捕我
- Get on your knees.
- You can't fuckin' arrest me!
快跪下
Knees, now!
我只是要回家
I'm just tryin' to get home, bruh!
我们不该进监狱
We ain't tryin' to go to jail,
you feel me?
我们只是要回家
We just tryin' to get home.
We just tryin' to get home. . .
也许你刚才就该好好想想
Maybe you should've thought about that,
而不是像个庞克猪一样
before you started acting like a punk-ass bitch.
你不能骂他
Don't call my partner no bitch.
你这个混蛋警察
You's a bitch-ass nigger, for real.
叫我“混蛋警察”？
Did you call me a "bitch-ass nigger"?
- 别乱说
- 混蛋黑鬼
- Don't fuckin' say that.
- Bitch-ass nigger, huh?
凭什么，我什么也没干
What the fuck! I ain't do shit!
操
Fuck!
我扳不动他的手
I can't get his fucking arm!
- 手翻过来
- 你压到我的头了
- Roll over!
- You're on my head, man!
手翻过来
Roll over!
你竟然开枪打我
You fuckin'. . .
You fuckin' shot me, bruh.
你开枪打我，我还有个女儿
You shot me. I got a daughter.
起来
Get up, bruh!
- 把他拉开
- 他什么也没干
- Get him out!
- He didn't do nothing!
- 快点
- 奥斯卡，起来
- Go! Go!
- Oscar, get up, bruh!
叫救护车，他快死了
Call an ambulance!
Man, he's dying, man!
快开车
Get this train out of here!
- 退后
- 干什么
- Back up!
- What the fuck!
快走
Get out of here.
快开车
Get the train out of here, now!
快
Move!
为什么车还不开走
Why isn't this train moving!
- 你干嘛？
- 快走
- What did you do?!
- Let's go!
进去
Get in there!
弗鲁特韦尔站发生枪击，代号3，请求医疗支援
Shots fired, Fruitvale. Code 3.Stage fire and medical.
你在想什么？
What the fuck happened?
啊？
Huh?
看着我，看着我好吗？
Look at me. Can you look at me?
- 他向我开枪
- 你坚持住
- He shot me.
- You stay right here.
我还有一个女儿
Shot me. . . I got a. . . a daughter.
别闭上眼睛
Keep your eyes open.
操
Fuck.
快接啊
Come on, talk.
苏菲娅？
Sophina?
警察抓了奥斯卡他们
The police, they got Oscar and them.
我听见有动静，不知道是不是枪声
I heard something and I don't know
if it was a beanbag. . .
苏菲娅，冷静，我没听清你说什么
Sophina, honey, calm down.
I can't hear you.
- 奥斯卡和你在一起吗？
- 没有，他和警察在站台上面
- Is Oscar there with you?
- No, he's upstairs with the police.
我们现在想上去找他们
But we're downstairs
and we're trying to get up to them,
- 但警察不让我们上去
- 奥斯卡被抓了吗？
- and they're not letting us upstairs.
-  Did Oscar get arrested?
不清楚，我估计是
I don't know, but I think so, Wanda.
我等下再打给你
OK, I'm gonna call you back.
那是谁？
Who's that for?
- 请问那是谁？
- 让开
- Sorry, who's that for?
- Stay back.
那是谁，那是谁？
Who's that for?
Who is that for?
为什么不告诉我发生了什么事
Why can't you tell me what is going on?
到底怎么了，告诉我怎么回事？
What is the problem?
Tell me what's going on?
贾森，贾森，怎么回事，怎么回事？
Jason! Jason! What happened?
What happened!
- 警察向他开枪
- 怎么回事？
- They fuckin' shot him!
- What happened?
警察无缘无故向奥斯卡背部开枪
They shot Oscar in his fuckin' back
for no reason, man!
他人呢，奥斯卡在哪？
Where is he?
Where is Oscar! Where is he?
奥斯卡在哪？
Where is Oscar? Where is he!
到底怎么了？
What is going on?
他在哪？
Where is he?
奥斯卡，能听到吗？
Oscar, can you hear me?
我还有个女儿
I have a daughter. . .
粘好，套上
Tape here. Bag him.
- 求求你
- 你感觉如何？
- Please. . .
- That's how you feel?
我男朋友在上面
My boyfriend is. . .
My boyfriend is up there, OK?
你不明白
You don't understand. Please. . .
我男朋友在上面
Please, my boyfriend is up there, OK?
- 请让我上去
- 你要向我们开枪吗？
- You need to let me up there.
- Y'all gonna shoot us too?
- 旺达
- 苏菲娅
- Wanda. . .
- Sophina. . .
我想上去，但警察就是不让
Yeah, been trying to get up there,
and they're not letting me up.
- 奥斯卡人呢？
- 天啊，天啊
- Where's Oscar?
- Oh, my God. . . Oh, my God.
你们把他怎么了？
What did you do to him?
你们杀了他，你们把他怎么了？
Did you fucking kill him!
What did you do to him?
交给我们，卡洛斯，我们会处理
We have it, Carlos.
Don't worry, we'll take care of it.
你现在没事了
You're all right now.
我要确定他没事
I need to make sure that he's OK!
他是我孩子的父亲
That's my fucking baby's daddy right there!
我要和他待着
OK, I need to be next to him!
你们带他去哪？
Where y'all taking him?
- 你们带他去哪？
- 去高地医院
- Where are you taking him?
- He's going to Highland.
放开我
Get off me!
旺达，警察向奥斯卡开枪
Wanda, they shot Oscar.
警察说他还活着，但是眼睛睁不开了
They say he's alive,
but his eyes was closed.
他们带他去高地医院，你马上来接我们
They're taking him to Highland,
you gotta come get us right now.
- 我马上来
- 操
- I'm on my way.
- Oh, fuck.
伤者情况？
What do you got for me?
22岁男性，后肩胛骨中枪
Twenty-two year old male,
posterior scapula GSW.
中枪时脸朝下躺着，倒数三声，一、二、三
He was lying face-down when he was shot.
On three. One, two, three.
- 血压多少？
- 收缩压70
- What was his blood pressure?
- Seventy systolic.
- 事发时他四肢在动吗？
- 是的，手臂和大腿
- Was he moving his limbs?
- Yes. Moving arms and legs.
给我一根胸管
I'm gonna need a chest tube.
我们得马上送他上去
We gotta get him upstairs right away.
你好，我儿子叫奥斯卡·朱利叶斯·格兰特三世
Excuse me, my son is Oscar Julius Grant III .
他中枪了，警察让我过来
He's been shot and they told me to come here.
- 格什么
- 格兰特
- G-R. . .
- A-N-T, yes.
他在手术，去重症监护室
OK, he's in surgery.
Go to the ICU room. . .
- 怎么走？
- 在那边
- And that is where?
- Right over there.
天啊，希望他没事
Oh Lord, please let him be safe.
准备输血
Get that blood in.
剪刀
Scissors.
吸管
Suction.
嘿
Hey.
- 嘿
- 有消息吗？
- Hey.
- Any news?
还没消息
No, no news yet.
- 混蛋
- 嘿嘿嘿
- Motherfuckers. . .
- Hey, hey, hey.
别闹事
Hey, no. Listen, none of that.
别闹事，别在这里惹事
None of that.
This is not the time or the place.
明白吗？
OK?
怎么一点消息也没有
Why ain't they said nothin' yet?
我们等吧
We waitin'.
别担心
Come on.
我们要对他有信心
Hey, we gotta keep him positive.
让他们各司其职
We gotta let these people do their jobs.
他没事的
He's gonna be fine.
现在把所有精力都放奥斯卡身上
Let's put all our energy
towards Oscar right now.
我知道你们很愤怒，但是我们必须给他打气
I know y'all are upset,
but we got to lift him up.
我们必须给他打气
Let's keep him lifted up.
- 我不知道
- 没事的
- I don't know.
- It's OK.
- 我感觉不好
- 冷静点
- I feel, I feel weird. . .
- Come on man, calm down.
你们听到妈妈的话了
Y'all heard Mom.
- 贾森太太？
- 什么事？
- Ms. Johnson?
- Yes?
- 医生有话跟你说
- 他怎么样？
- The doctor's going to speak to you.
- How is he?
贾森，你也知道你儿子中枪
Ms. Johnson, as you know,
your son's been shot.
我们在全力抢救，不过他很危险
Now, we stabilized him,
but he's critical.
危险，什么意思？
Critical, what is that?
他大量内出血
Well, he has massive internal bleeding,
我们必须切除他的右肺
and we had to remove the right lung.
切肺，那他以后怎么呼吸？
His lung? How. . .
how's he going to be able to breathe?
他现在靠呼吸机
He's on a breathing machine right now.
他的呼吸很稳定
So, his breathing is stable.
主要的问题是内出血
The main problem is the internal bleeding.
操
Damn. . .
我们很难让血止住
Now, we've had some difficulty
stopping the bleeding,and getting his blood to clot.
还在观察他的输血反应
He hasn't fully responded
to the transfusions yet.
他一定会没事的对吗？
But he's gonna make it, right?
He's gonna make it?
我向你保证我们会尽全力
I promise you we're going to do
everything possible. . .
安静
Hey! Hey!
- 求求你
- 我们会尽全力
- Please. . .
- We'll do what we can.
求求你们尽全力
Please do what you can.
救不活奥斯卡别出来
Don't come back out here
without Osc, nigga.
一定要救救他，救救奥斯卡
Bring him out, man. Bring Osc out.
我们得给他打气
We gotta lift him up, y'all.
我们要给奥斯卡打气
We got to lift Oscar up.
我不敢相信事情会这样
I can't even believe this,
man, we here, bruh.
- 我知道
- 我不敢相信
- I know.
- I can't believe this.
他是个斗士
Y'all know he's a fighter, man.
- 他会挺过来
- 混蛋警察
- He'll make it.
- Bitch-ass police.
他一定会没事
He's gonna be all right.
大家都来祈祷
Y'all, let's pray.
都来祈祷
Let's pray.
万能的主啊
Heavenly Father
我们向你屈膝
we kneel before you
希望你向这个孩子伸出援手
and ask you to put healing
hands around your child.
我们请求你赐予这些医生力量
We ask you, dear Lord,
to operate through these doctors.
赐予他们双手力量去救他
Breathe strength ίnto theίr hands, Lord,
as they work on hίm .
我们请求你救活他
We're askίng you rίght now to heal hίm .
救活他，万能的主
Oh, heal him , dear Lord.
让我们能重见他的笑颜
So we can hold hίm
and see hίs smίle agaίn.
以你之名，阿门
ln your name, we pray. Amen.
他一定会没事
He's gonna be all right.
他没能挺过来
He didn't make it.
我要看看他
I need to see him.
你可以看看他
OK, you can see him.
不过你不能进房间或者碰他
But they don't want you to go
into the room or touch him,
因为他们认为这是凶杀
because they ruled it a homicide.
我要看看他
I need to see him.
- 我带她进去
- 好吧
- I can take her.
- OK.
要我陪你去吗？
You want me to go with you?
不用
No.
不用，他是我的儿子
No, that's my baby.
是我让他坐地铁
I told him to take the train.
I told him to catch the BART.
我没想到事情会这样
I didn't know they were going to hurt my baby.
我应该让他开车去
I should've just let him drive.
我应该让他开车去，我只想他没事
I should've just let him drive,
but I wanted to keep him safe.
让我进去抱抱他
You gotta let me hug him.
求求你，让我抱抱他
Please, let me hug him.
求求你
Please. Please. . .
他不想孤单一人
He didn't like to be alone.
起来，T，起来
Come on, T.Come on, baby.
我们得走了
We got to go.
要走了？
You got to go?
回去睡觉
Shh. Go back to bed.
Go back to bed, OK? OK. . .
爸爸呢？
Where's Daddy?
有目击者用他们的手机拍下了
弗鲁特韦尔地铁站的这场枪击事件
这段视频在旧金山湾区引发一系列抗议和骚乱
涉事警察被开除
旧金山湾区地铁警察相关负责人辞职
枪杀奥斯卡警察被逮捕并被控一级谋杀罪
涉事警察声称他误把手枪当成电击枪
陪审团认定他犯有过失杀人罪
被判在州监狱服刑2年
并于服刑11个月后释放
奥斯卡·朱利叶斯·格兰特三世
2009年1月1日早上9:15去世
年仅22岁
弗鲁特韦尔车站
加州，奥克兰
2013年1月1日
下午2:15
（为奥斯卡·格兰特伸张正义）
塔蒂阿娜·格兰特
安息吧
奥斯卡·格兰特
TLF中文字幕站 http://sub.eastgame.org/
微博地址：http://t.sina.com.cn/tlfsubs/
豆瓣小站：http://site.douban.com/127446/